(fanfare music)
- [Voiceover] Hi and welcome.
I am Hammeh and in this new video series,
I'll be walking you
through fun extra facts
and potential backstory behind the heroes
in Overwatch that we discover
through their in-game voice lines.
Before any map starts during
the game on various triggers,
Overwatch heroes chat with
and react to each other
in some funny in-game voice interactions.
These give us some great
insights into hero character,
interesting back stories,
and even some things
in the story that haven't
been shown in the game yet.
In this video, we're
looking at Genji's story
through his interactions
with fellow heroes
and the world around him.
The ex-Overwatch agent has found peace
with his new existence as a Cyborg.
Although he still has issues to settle
with his brother Hanzo,
the circumstances around their parting,
and their family's criminal past.
Even though he's been
through some great trials
in his life, we can see
that Genji still has time
for a bit of humor and wisdom as well.
From some of his voice lines, we can see
that Zenyatta's benevolent
wisdom and tutorship
has rubbed off a bit on Genji.
- Revenge takes only the one who seeks it.
- [Voiceover] And Genji
still got a sense of humor.
Here's one line he can come out with.
- My name is green cyborg ninja dude.
That was actually mentioned on Twitter
by Senior Game Designer
and story guru Michael Chu
from the Overwatch team
when Genji was announced.
A lot of community saw Genji in the art
and all of his phrases
were quite commonly used
in trying to describe him.
"Green cyborg ninja dude"
when he didn't have a name.
Although this is kind of said as a joke,
we're a little bit sad that Genji
can't enjoy one of his
favorite foods anymore.
Even though he seems to
see some humor in it.
- [Genji] Ramen! (sighs) It's
just not the same anymore.
- [Voiceover] If you've read
the bios of the Overwatch cast,
then you know that Genji
and Hanzo have a shared
and troubled family history.
Both sons of the Shimada Clan,
Hanzo took a path of duty
where Genji showed little interest
in the family criminal business.
Following the untimely
death of their father,
tensions mounted between the two
until a violent confrontation
ended in Hanzo leaving Genji
on the verge of death.
The two have a number of interactions.
We'll show some of the
Genji led ones here.
We're led to believe to start with
that the two haven't seen each
other since that fateful day
from this conversation.
- What's wrong Hanzo?
Don't you recognize me?
- You may call yourself my brother,
but you are not the Genji I knew.
- [Voiceover] Since
leaving Genji for dead,
Hanzo's remorse caused
him to reject his duty
of ruling the Shimada.
Instead, he wandered the
world in search of redemption
and tried to find ways
to reclaim his honor.
Genji would actually comment
on his brother's fall from
grace when he sees him.
- So this is what has become of you...
A pity.
- [Voiceover] In spite of
what they've been through,
Genji still wishes for his own
brother to find a new path.
Perhaps he's forgiven him
for what he's done to him.
- It is not too late to
change your course, brother.
- You are mistaken, brother.
I am beyond redemption.
We could have built an empire together.
- That was your dream. Not mine.
- [Voiceover] An element
of brotherly rivalry
still remains though,
when Genji gets a kill
on an enemy Hanzo, you can
still hear this come out.
- I am victorious this time, brother.
I learned that from my brother.
- [Voiceover] Another character that Genji
has a deep history with, is
the omnic monk, Zenyatta.
After working with Overwatch to dismantle
his family's criminal empire,
Genji couldn't come to terms
with his new cyborg form and nature.
He roamed the world to
try and find meaning
before coming across Zenyatta.
He initially rejected his wisdom,
but then, Zenyatta
eventually became his mentor
and his guru of sorts helped him
to accept his dual existence
as both being man and machine.
The pupil-master relationship
and deep bond between the two
is evident in a lot of their lines.
Here's a mention that
Zenyatta throws to Genji.
- It is good to fight alongside
one of my brightest pupils.
- [Voiceover] When Genji kills
Zenyatta on another team,
he likes to take a little dig at Zenyatta
in a "apprentice has become the
master" kind of fashion tea.
- I have the upper hand this time, master.
- [Voiceover] Mercy is
a pretty key character
in Genji's story.
Genji is left on the brink of death
following the violent
confrontation we mentioned
between him and Hanzo.
It was Dr. Angela Ziegler,
or Mercy, who rescues him
from death on behalf of Overwatch.
Even though the two of them
haven't worked together
since those days, Mercy still has concern
for her ex-patient's welfare,
as shown by this line.
- You seem well, Genji.
- I am a different man now. I am whole.
- [Voiceover] And, although
Genji may have struggled
with his cyborg form created
by Overwatch to save his life,
he's still seemingly grateful to Mercy
for what she's done for him, shown here.
- You've rescued me again, Dr. Ziegler.
- [Voiceover] And the
rest of the Overwatch cast
of heroes and villains, Genji
has a few other interactions
and we picked a few for you here.
Firstly, with Genji and Winston.
From the Overwatch animated short "Recall"
and his voice lines, we know that Winston
is a big Overwatch geek and loves the idea
of Overwatch reforming and
working with his old team again.
He's equally enthusiastic when
talking to Genji about this.
- Genji, this is just like old times.
- Our paths cross for now. As
to the future, we shall see.
- [Voiceover] Genji's
interaction with Zarya
is also quite interesting.
Zarya has very strong
feelings against omnics.
They're a big part of her character
given her experience with
currently battling them in Syberia
and also, them being one of the reasons
that she had to give up her weightlifting
and professional sports career.
She's not immediately ready to
trust Genji, as we hear here.
- How do I trust a man
who is half machine?
- The heart of a man
still beats inside me.
- [Voiceover] Of all the
characters in the world
of Overwatch, it feels like
Genji has a huge grounding
and an array of lines and interactions
that trigger when he spawns
into certain maps and levels.
He has lines with several
characters in many levels.
Here's a selection of our favorites.
The first place we'll start
is home, for Genji anyway.
Hanamura is the home of the Shimada Clan,
Genji and Hanzo's ancestral home.
Genji enjoyed a life of luxury
and privileges as a child.
As the clan master's youngest
son, he enjoyed a playboy
and carefree lifestyle
in spite of excelling
at his ninja training.
We can discover a fraction
of how he spent his time
in this line, when Genji spawns
in the Hanamura attacking
spawn, "The Arcade."
- [Genji] I pass many an hour
of my misspent youth here.
- [Voiceover] And as part of the
master and student relationship,
it's also interesting
to see Zenyatta take interest
in Genji's upbringing.
- [Zenyatta] So this is where you grew up.
You must show me around.
- [Voiceover] Another
part of the Over-verse
that Genji has a deep
connection with is Nepal.
It seems from looking at the map,
that when he accepted
Zenyatta's mentorship
after his period of wandering,
Genji came here to spend
some time with the Shambali,
the order of monks led by Mondatta.
It feels as though amongst the omnics
and the snowcap mountains, Genji managed
to find some connection
with the world again.
He has several lines on Nepal
that show his affinity, joy,
and affection to be part of
the monastery and community.
- [Genji] (sighs) Just setting foot here
sets my soul at ease.
Only here, do I not feel outcast.
This is my home now.
- [Voiceover] As for the
evidence that Genji was here,
we'll save some for a Nepal map video,
but we can see Genji's room
here in Nepal on stage one
with a picture of the Shimadas,
what perhaps was once his robe,
and what could well be his sword.
We found this line on his sword
that we think actually triggers
when he goes into the room.
- [Genji] This is my sword, Ryu Ichimonji.
- [Voiceover] Now, when trying
to work out this sword name,
apparently "Ryu" means "dragon"
and "ichimonji" something
like "figure one,"
a fighting stance, and it
could also refer to the shape
of a katana blade being similar
to the Japanese way of
writing, the number "one."
Ichimonji is used in
a bunch of sword names
in the English translation
in some games already.
Any ideas on that? Please let us know.
Thanks a bunch for the help on that one.
As part man and part
machine, Genji, of course,
has a natural interest
in the fate of omnics
out in the Overwatch world.
King's Row is currently
the scene of great tension
between omnics and humans
and Genji is certainly aware
of this in this interaction with Zenyatta.
- [Genji] Does the
suffering of the omnics here
trouble you, master?
- [Zenyatta] It does.
My brother, Mondatta, gave
much to improve their lives,
but it was not to be.
- [Voiceover] We know, of course,
that Mondatta paid the
ultimate price with his life,
as seen by the events
of the "Alive" short,
where Widowmaker assassinates him in spite
of Tracer's best efforts.
Memorials to Mondatta in King's Row
are physical there still.
However, with escalating tension
between the people there,
whether his memory and teachings
will help diffuse the
crisis remain to be seen.
Even though Genji's found
some peace with his existence,
he still feels out of place on occasion.
In Numbani, a city where
humans and omnics are meant
to be coexisting happily
together for quite some time,
he's still not quite at ease,
as we can see from this line.
- [Genji] Even here, I feel an outcast.
- [Voiceover] Regardless
of any struggles though,
Genji has certainly found a
new appreciation of beauty
and life on his travels.
He can now see beauty in places
that he hasn't even seen
before, as shown by this line,
when he revisits Watchpoint: Gibraltar.
- [Genji] It is beautiful here.
I could never appreciate it before.
- [Voiceover] Thanks
very much for tuning in
to my Hero Voice Lines and Story series.
If you like this video, please
hit that "like" button below
and subscribe and comment
with what lines you enjoy most
and most importantly, what
hero you'd like to see next.
I really appreciate hearing you all think.
You can check out more
videos from this series
our easter eggs and map lore series,
as well as regular Overwatch
commentated gameplay
on the channel too.
Check out all the links below.
Stay tuned to the channel as well
for our quick gameplay
tips series coming soon
to help you guys who are
new get started with a bang.
Thanks much for tuning in.
I've been Hammeh, and take it easy.
(triumphant music)